## ERIC P. HEWITT, JD, MBA, ALM

www.linkedin.com/in/EricPHewitt | EricPHewitt@gmail.com | (312) 522-7101

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Strategic thinker, project/program manager, and U.S. military veteran with strong consulting experience to C-level leadership in dynamic, fast-paced environments. Proven abilities in research, analytical thinking, project management, leadership, mature judgment, working independently, and problem solving. Possess a comprehensive background in research, data collection, triage, solution development, and recommendation implementation. Bring extensive knowledge in project management, dynamic presentations, stakeholder expectation management, and analytical problem solving. JD/MBA graduate with a Masters in Sustainability from Harvard University.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Berkshire Hathaway HS / Eric Hewitt LLC | Fort Lauderdale, FL Licensed Real Estate Consultant (Self-employed)

2021/2017 - Present

- Forged, managed, and leveraged relationships with clients, colleagues, and industry leaders
- Drafted letters of intent, worked with private equity (PE) partners to acquire CRE in the 5-50MM range, assisted in financial analysis and financing
- Identified prospects and individually tailored business proposal communication; autonomously managed and prioritized multiple priorities and deadlines; established and employed a tech-based communication plan

### Victor Tech | Chicago, IL CFO & Co-Founder

2017 - 2018

- Analyzed the organizational direction and implemented a novel strategic sales plan to fund ongoing capital requirements; identified measurable success criteria, created and managed the budget for iOS development
- Modeled the marketing plan in excel, created three financial statements, evaluated and reduced risk during the product launch using data and scenario analysis
- Orchestrated the product's technology reconfiguration and launched a new veteran-focused application in iOS
- Coached, trained, and mentored two finance interns from China

# Financial Industry Regulatory Authority (FINRA) | Chicago, IL Legal Extern (Attorney – Enforcement)

Fall 2018

- Conducted a stakeholder analysis and designed a new research request procedure for future interns; implemented the project's plan using Kotter's enhanced 8 Accelerator's change management framework
- Standardized, digitized, updated, and streamlined the onboarding training manual reducing 15-20 emails into one PDF file with hyperlinked training materials for new hires; created a new standard adopted as corporate policy with streamlined templates and faster processes by implementing a change management skillset
- Self-taught a new technology program reducing over 900 emails into a few selected evidentiary requests; direct working experience in regulatory guidelines, compliance, and oversight operations

## Harvard Management Company $\mid$ Boston, MA

2013

Trading Associate, Extern Middle Office - High Yield Credit Desk

- Presented daily analytical reports detailing credit and FX risk for the trader of a billion-dollar credit portfolio; provided portfolio managers the ability to make strategic investment decisions; hedged foreign exchange portfolio risk and traded futures on FX to eliminate currency fluctuations
- Executed a nightly PNL report, calculating all positions traded and portfolio risk for upcoming trading day
- Entered all trades for the desk and traded \$50M-\$100M in credit derivatives per day with 100% accuracy

# Morgan Stanley, Blackrock, Rothschild & The United States Treasury | Various Locations Associate & Analyst

2006 - 2009

Assessed 10K and 10Q reports to analyze investments for Morgan Stanley; gained skill in equity / debt analysis

- Designed 15+ pitch book proposals, provided market color, and recommended investment asset-allocations; worked independently with minimal supervision
- Anticipated client's investment needs and delivered bespoke financial solutions; created 300+ new business proposals to potential wealth management clients; brought \$10M in new investments to the firm
- Ran risk analysis applications on Blackrock's \$10T asset portfolios and conveyed results to 200+ portfolio managers through daily or ad hoc reports created in Aladdin
- Analyzed compliance guidelines for external portfolios and created system flags for the client's traders
- Served as a Project Manager with the United Stated Treasury Department, tasked with transforming a division in OMB to paperless invoice processing; reduced payment processing time by 33% using \$100K in funds already allocated for the department; collaborated with IT, management, and budgeting to foster a creative solution
- Designed and turned deal pitch books for Rothschild as a Mergers & Acquisitions Analyst; computed the transaction comps, trading comps, discounted cash flow, and cost of capital; sold Cornell companies for approximately \$500M

#### MILITARY SERVICE

United States Army National Guard | Various Locations
United States Marine Corps Reserve | Various Locations
Operations & Project Manager (Non-Commissioned Officer)

2004 - 2007

1999 - 2004

- Consulted with 10-20 federal government C-level officers on missions; utilized problem-solving abilities to create mission plans; awarded two Meritorious Masts for exemplary conduct and operational effectiveness
- Planned, presented, and executed several multi-faceted critical missions and debriefed officers on the mission's impact; built mission-specific teams, managed 12 direct reports, and trained 40 junior personnel
- Worked independently within an elite special operations capable two-man team; demonstrated outside-the-box thinking in creating innovative solutions to mission objectives
- Process-mapped missions, built guiding coalitions, identified milestones and initiatives, enlisted personnel, implemented project/mission plans, sustained the mission momentum, reviewed results, and adjusted when necessary
- Responsible for the strategic direction of mission-critical combat operations in a foreign country; led by example and used a change management skill-set daily in a constantly changing fast-paced environment

### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Developer | PDX Code Guild (expected 4/2023)

Juris Doctor & Master of Business Administration | University of Notre Dame

Master of Liberal Arts, Sustainability | Harvard University

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, Finance & Management | Georgetown University

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Climate Change and Corporate Profitability: The Effects of Greenhouse Gasses and Sustainability Strategies on Stock Price Performance, Harvard University (2017)

> Sections of Sivolella v. AXA Equitable Life Insurance Company (2016 WL 4487857) Eudaimonia: The Georgetown Philosophical Review; An Argument for Dualism (2006)

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Excel modeling (Cert. from Wharton), LexisNexis, WestLaw, R, Bloomberg, SPSS, Tableau, SQL, SharePoint, Cyber Security, Project Management (Cert. from Google, PMP expected 1/2023)

Passed both the NY and FL bar exams on the first attempt

### AWARDS/HONORS/OTHER

Elected Senator, Harvard Graduate Council FourBlock Alumni, Columbia University Hobbies: chess player, reading, long-range shooting